FILIPPO SERAFINI

Computer Engineer

Via G. Loreti 21
Fabriano (AN), 60044, Italy
+39 339 1935823
filippo.serafini95@gmail.com
https://filipposerafini.github.io/

SUMMARY

I just graduated with merits from University of Bologna and now I am ready to face new experiences, with the aim of learning new things, expand my knowledge and improve myself

I believe that teamwork is the best way to tackle complex problems and make the work lighter, and I am used to address every situation with a positive attitude

EDUCATION

Scientific High School Diploma

Liceo Scientifico Statale Vito Volterra, Fabriano

SEPTEMBER 2009 - JULY 2014

JULY 2012 - Study Trip in Royal Tunbridge Wells, UK - Work experience at Halls Bookshop SEPTEMBER 2012 - APRIL 2013 - Impara ad Intraprendere XXI Edition, Confindustria Ancona MAY 2013 - Director Assistant for Machiavelli's comedy "La Mandragola" DECEMBER 2013 - 50° Convegno Giubileo Pirandelliano, Centro Nazionale Studi Pirandelliani

Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna, Bologna

SEPTEMBER 2014 - OCTOBER 2017

Final Grade - 110/110 cum laude

Dissertation Name - Software per il labeling di immagini per l'addestramento di algoritmi di deep-learning

EXPERIENCES

AGESCI - Associazione Guide e Scouts Cattolici Italiani

Gruppo Scout AGESCI Fabriano 2, Fabriano

SEPTEMBER 2003 - AUGUST 2014

Formula SAE Team - Electronic Division Member

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna, Bologna

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

LANGUAGES

Italian - Native Speaker

English - Fluent - Cambridge FCE

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- C/C++
- Java
- Python
- C#
- JavaScript
- Bash Scripting
- MATLAB

Programming Skills

- Software Development (Git)
- Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, XML, Java EE)
- Database (SQL, Hibernate)
- Frameworks (OpenCV, GTK+, .NET)
- Platforms (GNU Linux, Microsoft Windows, Android)

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Problem solving
- Creative thinking
- Project management

(SOME) PROJECTS

Labeler - 2017

Training tool for deep-learning algorithm developed in C

Room8 - 2017

Expenses management application developed in C#

GEnerA - 2016

Web application *winner of HACKreativity*, an hackathon organized by Fondazione Aristide Merloni